Finding Aid for Financial Operations (University of Michigan) records, 1837-2004
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Operating Records of Buildings, Divisions, and Other Units
  - Power Plant
    - Power Plant Operating Expense Distribution, 1925-1958; 4 folders (Box 27)
    - Power Plant Radiation Table, 1931-1932 (Box 27)
    - Power Plant Report Correspondence, 1923-1935; 1951-1952 (Box 27)
  - Revision Committee for the Manual for Uniform Financial Reporting, 1973-1976; 2 folders (Box 27)
  - Space Inventory and Utilization, 1965-1982
    - 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 27)
    - 1970-1973, 5 folders (Box 27)
    - 1974-1975, 3 folders (Box 28)
    - 1977 (Box 28)
    - 1980 (Box 28)
    - 1979-1982, 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Student Fee Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 28)
  - University Audits, 1967-1969 (Box 28)
  - Women's Hospital Space Inventory, 1979 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous Reports, Studies and Volumes
  Miscellaneous Reports, Studies, and Volumes, contains a number of unusual and interesting items, recording information such as the barracks count of soldiers stationed at the University during World War I and coal purchases made between 1894-1905, as well as reports on the University shops (1933), its registration system (1926), the use of punch cards on campus (ca. 1935), staff and facilities, (1950-1951) and other subjects.
  - Barracks Count During World War I, undated (Box 21)
  - Levi Barbour Estate Record Book, 1925-1926 (Box 21)
  - Coal Purchases, 1894-1905 (Box 21)
  - Financial Operations Survey, 1927 (Box 21)
  - Henderson Study of Governmental Structures at Michigan Educational Institutions, circa 1933 (Box 21)
  - Investment Programs, 1960; 1961; 1963 (Box 21)
  - Operations and Maintenance Costs, 1924 (Box 21)
  - Overtime Policy, 1965-1966 (Box 21)
  - Purchasing Procedures, 1941-1942 (Box 21)
  - Registration System, 1926 (Box 21)
  - Report on University of Michigan Shops, 1933 (Box 21)
  - Storage of Records, 1965 (Box 21)
  - Student Billings, 1960 (Box 21)
  - Study of Buildings and Grounds Operations and Maintenance, 1924 (Box 21)
  - Study of Staff and Facilities, 1950-1951 (Box 22)
  - Use of Punch Cards, circa 1935 (Box 22)
  - Year Round Operations, 3 terms, 1965 (Box 22)
  - American Council on Education, 1960-1961 (Box 28)
  - Freedom of Information Act, 1977 (Box 28)
  - J.C. Christensen
    - Articles and Presentations, 1912-1941 (Box 28)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944; undated (Box 28)
    - North Central Association Conference, 1936 (Box 28)
- Accounting Office Records
  Accounting Office Records, detail the operations of the Financial Operations between 1900 and 1967. Included are sets of general records (1914-1941), minutes of various meetings (1945-1967), and enrollment statistics (1900-1955). Also included is information regarding university salary structures between 1900-1962.
  - General Records
    - 1914-1921 (Box 22)
      (including General Ledger Accounts description, 1915)
    - 1924-1932, 2 folders (Box 22)
      (primarily re. office reorganization)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 22)
    - 1937-1938 (Box 22)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 22)
    - 1940-1941
      - General (Box 22)
      - Outline of Purchasing and Accounting Procedures (Box 22)
  - Minutes
    - Controllers Office
      - 1945-1949 (Box 22)
      - October 1957-June 1958 (Box 22)
      - July 1958-June 1959 (Box 22)
      - October 1961-December 1962 (Box 22)
      - 1963 (Box 22)
      - 1964 (Box 22)
      - 1965 (Box 22)
      - 1966-1968 (Box 22)
    - Education Committee
      - And February 1968, October 1967 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
    - Staff
      - 1961-1967 (Box 22)
    - Systems and Data Processing Coordinating Committee
      - 1965-1966 (Box 22)
    - Vice-President for Business Affairs
      - 1966-1967 (Box 22)
  - Enrollment Statistics
    - 1900-1949 (Box 23)
    - 1950-1955 (Box 23)
  - Salary Structures
    - 1900-1928 (Box 23)
    - 1928-1943 (Box 23)
    - 1943-1962 (Box 23)
    - Study of Faculty Salaries, 1939-1940; 1940-1947 (Box 23)
    - Study of Teaching Fellows Salaries, 1942-1943 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Engraved metal plates, undated (Box 23)
    - Audits, 1940; 1942-1943 (Box 23)
    - Annual Audits of Student Organizations, 1931-1951; 19 volumes (Box 24)
  - Photographs
    - Horace H. Rackham School of Graduate Studies, construction, 1936-1937 (Box 25)
    - University Hospital, construction, 1920-1921; 3 folders (Box 25)
- Correspondence
  Correspondence includes letters and memos within Financial Operations from 1994-2004.
  - 1994 (Box 29)
  - 1995, 4 folders (Box 29)
  - 1996, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - 1997, 2 folders (Box 29)
  - 1998, 3 folders (Box 29)
  - 1999 (Box 30)
  - 2000, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - 2001, 6 folders (Box 30)
  - 2002, 5 folders (Box 30)
  - 2003, 3 folders (Box 30)
  - 2004, 7 folders (Box 31)
- Student Fee Rates, 1950-1996
  The Student Fee Rates, 1950-1996, series contains booklets listing fee rates for various programs. The booklets also contain fee regulations, such as stipulations for reduced fees, refund of fees, and supplementary fees, as well as residence regulations.
  - 1950-1979 (Box 34)
  - 1980-1996 (Box 34)
- UM Economic Impact, 1980-2001
  UM Economic Impact, 1980-2001 contains reports, articles, and statistics analyzing the university's economic impact, in particular the impact it has made on Washtenaw County. Annual gross pay by zipcode reports are a prominent feature of this series, demonstrating how the university contributed to the livelihood of many local communities.
  - Impact on Washtenaw County
    - 1980-1987 (Box 35)
    - 1988 (Box 35)
    - 1989, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - 1990 (Box 35)
    - 1991 (Box 35)
    - 1992 (Box 35)
    - 1993, 2 folders (Box 35)
    - 1994 (Box 35)
    - 1995 (Box 35)
    - 1996 (Box 35)
    - 1997 (Box 35)
    - 1999-2001 (Box 35)
    - Memos, 1985-1992 (Box 35)
  - Impact on State and Other Counties, 1997 (Box 35)
  - Medical Center Impact, 1986 (Box 35)
  - Vendor Paid Amount by County, 1988-1989 (Box 35)
Listing of Outsized Volumes
No. 1, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1914-1918
No. 2, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1918-1921
No. 3, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1921-1924
No. 4, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1924-1927
No. 5, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1927-1930
No. 6, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1930-1933
No. 7, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1933-1936
No. 8, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1936-1939
No. 9, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1939-1943
No. 10, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1943-1947
No. 11, Secretary's Journal of Receipts and Disbursements, 1947
No. 12, Inventory of Land Purchases and Major Construction, ca. 1914-1930
No. 13, Dormitory Records-Journals by Dormitory, 1933-1938
No. 14, Dormitory Records-Journals by Dormitory, 1938-1945
No. 15, Dormitory Records-Journals by Dormitory, 1945-1947
No. 16, Dormitory Records-Journal of Mosher-Jordan, 1930-1943
No. 17, Gifts-Journals, 1890-1903
No. 18, Gifts-Journals, 1903-1912
No. 19, Gift Account Abstracts, 1903-1908
No. 20, Hospital-Journals, 1926-1942
No. 21, Hospital-Journals, 1942-1947
No. 22, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1951-1952
No. 23, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1952-1953 [A-L]
No. 24, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1952-1953 [M-Z]
No. 25, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1931-1951 [Q-Z]
No. 26, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1931-1951 [A-D]
No. 27, Student Organizations-Daily Record of Debits & Credits, 1931-1951 [L-P]
No. 28, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 29, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 30, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 31, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 32, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 33, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 34, Trust Fund Records-Ledgers, ca. 1920-1945
No. 35, Trust Fund Records-Securities Records, ca. 1920-1950
No. 36, Trust Fund Records-Securities Records, ca. 1920-1950
No. 37, Trust Fund Records-Securities Records, ca. 1920-1950
No. 38, Trust Fund Records-Securities Records, ca. 1920-1950
No. 39, Trust Fund Records-Receipt Registers, 1932-1937
No. 40, Trust Fund Records-Receipt Registers, 1937-1941
No. 41, Trust Fund Records-Receipt Registers, 1941-1946
No. 42, Trust Fund Records-Receipt Registers, 1946-1948
No. 43, Trust Fund Records-Journals, 1922-1946
No. 44, Trust Fund Records-Journals, 1922-1937
No. 45, Trust Fund Records-Journals, 1937-1947
No. 46, Trust Fund Records-Ledger, 1922-1940
No. 47, Willow Run Airport-Accounts Receivable, 1950-1955
No. 48, Audit Reports of Michigan Auditor General-Bank Statements, 1931-1932
No. 49, Ledger of Alumni Contributions, 1932-1951
No. 50, Audit Reports of Michigan Auditor General-Monthly Balances, 1928-1931
No. 51, Income Records-State Fund Ledger, 1931-1948
No. 52, Land Records-Land Contracts, 1902-1916